Guide to the International Monitor Institute. Burma Videotapes, circa 1990-2002 RL.00605
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Burma Videotapes, circa 1990-2002, 287 videocassettes
  - Amateur footage: Karen National Union (KNU)/All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF) Refugee Camp, PAL Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 289, Video-cassette BU200)
    Refugees' Life and Front Line 1995
    A kitchen for student warriors; A school for children; Fun bath in mountain stream. Pleasure in time of turmoil.
    A prison
    ABSDF Camp
    A patriotic song "To the Heroes of Democracy"
  - Amateur Footage: Shots of refugees camps and Rangoon (1996), PAL Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 289, Video-cassette BU201)
    All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF) Camp and Students Warriors
    Song continued; the ceremony; a lunch banquet; video show of Daw Aung San Suu Kyi
    The prison and prisoners
    Army Day in Rangoon, March 27, 1996.
  - Amateur Footage: Army Day celebration in Rangoon, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 289, Video-cassette BU202)
    Army Day Celebration in Rangoon
  - Amateur Footage: Interviews with Burmese refugees, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 289, Video-cassette BU203)
    Interviews with refugees about living conditions in the camp.
    A refugee boy: "I want to go homeI want to see my parents happy."
  - Amateur Footage: Footage from Burma Diary, PAL Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 289, Video-cassette BU204)
    Tin Aung's Life
    "They tortured my brothers, and put them in prison. My other brother escaped and joined the All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF) and now he goes to the front line."
    "My father died in 1989 and I did not get to see him before that. I wanted to go but I could not."
    Tin Aung's two daughters
    Martyrs' Hill where Chit Po's father Myint Thein was laid.
  - Amateur Footage: Refugee Information, PAL Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 289, Video-cassette BU205)
    Refugees (Continued)
    (Poor audio quality)
    The sad boy Chit Po: A journey in the jungle and a Journey along River Moi
  - Amateur Footage: Refugee Information, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 289, Video-cassette BU206)
    Karen soldiers and All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF) Camp
  - Amateur Footage: All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF) Training Headquarters, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 289 and 303, Video-cassette BU207)
    Military training; Tin Aung 's interview.
  - Amateur Footage: Refugee Information, PAL VHS [TRT 0:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 289 and 303, Video-cassette BU208)
    Htin Aung's Family and Refugee Situation(1995)
    (Poor Audio in Interviews)
    Arriving Karen Refugees
    National Coalition Government of the Union of Burma (NCGUB) Office in Manaplaw
    All Burma Young Monk Union Camp
  - Amateur Footage: Refugee Living Conditions, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 289 and 303, Video-cassette BU209)
    Young Monk Union Office and the Refugee Situation
    Heavy rain and refugees under plastic camps.
  - Amateur Footage: Report from Rangoon, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (210) (Box 289 and 303, Video-cassette BU210)
    Army Day in Rangoon (The Army's 50th Anniversary)
    Footage of: marching soldiersin army parade; soldiers milling about; a dance debut; student band; young soldiers.
  - Amateur Footage: Refugee Health Care, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU211)
    Produced by: Karen Refugee Information Agency
    Hospital run by Dr. Cynthia Maung and the refugee camp; Karen National Union (KNU) Buddhist Ceremony; wet and muddy streets; songs and dances; blessings of a monk.
    Interview with a femalestudenton various kinds of torture by army personnel; an old soldier on details of massacre, disposal of bodies and the death of thousands; a student warrior's plea to the world.
  - Amateur Footage: Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU212)
    Tin Aung and Family in a make shift camp; difficulties faced by people; refugees crossing Karen National Union (KNU) check point National Coalition Government of the Union of Burma (NCGUB) office in Manaplaw; Young Monk Union office; rain in a refugee camp.
  - Amateur Footage: Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU213)
    From Burma Diary: 50th Anniversary of founding of Burma's army; army day paradein Rangoon; young soldiers of 16 and 17 are interviewed.
  - Amateur Footage: Refugee Situation -Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU214)
    Footage of: a hospital with young patients; laboratory; gun-toting boy; a muddy road to the Buddhist ceremony.
    Interview with State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC) victims. Former SLORC soldier."Tens of thousands killed by SLORC."
    A female Karen soldier: "My brother was killed."
    Torture Victims. Teary testimony of 1988 Massacre victims.
  - Amateur Footage: Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU215)
    Footage of: scenes and people in Burma; Thailand border; Burmese Mandolin and a song; a Burmese gentleman.
  - Amateur Footage: Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU216)
    Scenes of people in Burma and the Thai border.
  - Amateur Footage: Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU217)
  - Amateur Footage: Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU218)
    Scenes and people in Burma and the Thai border.
  - Amateur Footage: Burma Diary, PAL Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU219)
  - Amateur Footage: War Front Karen National Union (KNU), Part I, PAL VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU220)
    Footage of: KNU warriors after of a skirmish; bodies of State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC) soldiers; small Karen victory; view from the bunkers; captured flag; LI 118; 5th Division; corpses of SLORC young soldiers.
  - War Front Karen National Union (KNU), Continued, PAL VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU221)
    Captured weapons and communication equipment and boxes of ammunition.
  - Amateur Footage: Interview with Aung San Suu Kyi, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU222)
    Corruption becoming trademark in State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC)'s lifestyle. Economy is in terrible condition.
    Education is entirely wrong.
  - Daw Aung San Suu Kyi with Youth Wing Members, Speeches, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU223)
    General moral concerns. Misguided administration. Gambling rings in Burma. River Moi. (Thaung Yin Myit)
  - Amateur Footage: Refugee Information, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297 and 303, Video-cassette BU224)
    Students view performance scores. A kitchen in the middle of war. Makeshift hospital and patients.Dyingyoung Karen boy. Travel along the Moi river. People depend on boat transportation. Elephants in logging industry activities. Flag ceremony at All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF) camp.
  - Amateur Footage: Refugee Camp Religious Activities, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297 and 303, Video-cassette BU225)
    A Shin Byu Ceremony: temporary monks hood to dedicate Buddha; a Dobut dance; Buddha image; Htin Aung; a young Pho Thudaw.
  - Amateur Footage: Htin Aung's Activities, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:20:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU226)
    New Year's celebration in Bangkok; a makeshift tent at a refugee camp; Manilau, where Htin Auing lives; Htin Aung's Urban Student Warriors and City of Bangkok home.
  - Amateur Footage: From Burma Diary (1996), NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (Box 297, Video-cassette BU227)
    Footage from Burma Diary. Htin Aung out of Thailand to Australia. Departure lounge.
  - Amateur Footage: From Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU228)
    Htin Aung's home and guava fruits. Lumpany garden. Bangkok. Sapphire temple.
  - Amateur Footage: From Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU229)
    Interview with Htin Aung. He speaks about the death of his parents - a sad story of broken homes caused by the dictatorship.
  - Amateur Footage: From Burma Diary, PAL Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU230)
    Continued interview with Htin Aung: "We have to follow Daw Aung San Suu Kyi. Let's not say good bye. I'll meet you again."
  - Amateur Footage: From Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU231)
    Mrs. Htin Aung: "I am not happy. I want to go back home."
    Preparing to leave: "No retreat, no surrender. I have already served my country."
    Bangkok Airport: Htin Aung leaving home and revolution behind.
  - TV Myanmar: Tragic Stories of Burma, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:90:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU232)
    A story based on an exiled Burmese who returns home and discovers the amazing development.
    TV Myanmar production and SPDC perception of General Development under their authority. Social-economic development. Myanmar Oriental Bank. Myanmar's Business Convention Center. Shopping centers.
    Persuading foreign businessmen to invest in Burma. A traditional dance shown for business elite. Myanmar Airways.
    Burma's beautiful ancient treasures. Pagodas. Pagan, an ancient Burmese city. Magnificent View.
  - TV Myanmar: Not Even Gold (1997), NTSC VHS [TRT 00:90:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU233)
    TV Myanmar production on preventing involvement in the Sex Trade.
  - Footage from Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU234)
  - Amateur Footage: Upper Burma, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU235)
    Scenes from Burma: Moe Gaung market; vendors and beggars along the railways and roads.
  - Amateur footage: Footage from Burma diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU236)
    Produced by: Private Individual
    A boat trip in Thaung Yin Myit; Htin Aung's house; an unfinished bamboo hut; Twins ofHtin Aung; Naing Aung and the Chit Po's family; A refugee village
    Karen commander with walkie-talkie; A sound of war, an artillery shell
    A bunker Karen National Union (KNU) defense line; a game of dominos; lunch in the bunker
    Travelers in the troubled land; Mules carrying the loads
    Refugee children in line at school
  - Amateur Footage: Refugees, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU237)
    Teenagers with no foreseeable future; Huge playground; Wounded person on a stretcher
    A supply route, life line for the new-born village
    Talk about war; All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF) prepared for war
    Warriors at war
    Children at over-crowded school.
  - Amateur Footage: Refugees, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU238)
    Footage from refugee camps: a marble game; celebration in Manaplaw; boxing matches with General Bo Mya; horse drawn cart; Inlay lake; 40 peace boats.
  - Amateur Footage: Refugee camps, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU239)
    Interview with Chartate: "Student soldiers are my brothers."
    Wedding of Chatate; Karen marching band; shy bride and young groom with an uncertain future.
    Raw Footage
  - No Peace, No Mercy, Burma is Internally Displaced, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:45:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU240)
    Edited Report: Karen Refugee Relief
    Political stalematein Burma.
    A refugee sited: "A lot people including childrendied.I was forced to go."
    A child talked about the atrocities of Burmese army.
    A burning village and a cry of agony; people running for life
    Captured State Law and Order Restoration Council soldiers
    Burmese systematic campaign of ethnic cleansing.
    A forced Laborer: "I am too scared to refuse to work."
    Exodus of Karenni people in the jungle; "We left everything behind. I am afraid my family is dying of starvation."
    "My husband died, a victim of landmines."
    Forcibly relocated villages
    Pictures of human rights abuses by State Law and Order Restoration Council
    Rape victims, forced porterage, and forced relocation victimseverywhere
    Refugees in the rain: "We died of fever and diarrhea."
  - NLD Information, NTSC VHS [TRT 01:30:00] (4 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU241)
    National League for Democracy (NLD) Information
  - Footage from Burma Diary, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU242)
  - TV Myanmar: United We Will Reach the Sky (1999), NTSC VHS [TRT 00:45:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU243)
    TV Myanmar Production on the Rakhine (Yakhine) Regional Development projects.
    Film attempts to portray cooperation between soldiers and people; The Rakhine traditional Kyin wrestling ceremony
    Karen State development projects; Paan's new hospital
    Kachin state black markets
  - TV Myanmar: Sky - the Dream Square, PAL Betacam SP [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU244)
    TV Myanmar Production on Air Force.
  - TV Myanmar: Growth - Not a Dream, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:90:00] (Box 297, Video-cassette BU245)
    TV Myanmar Production and SPDC commentary on General Development under their authority. Social-economic development. Myanmar Oriental Bank. Myanmar'sBusiness Convention Center. Shopping centers. Persuading foreign businessmen to invest in Burma. A traditional dance shown for business elite. Myanmar Airways. Burma's beautiful ancient treasures. Pagodas. Pagan, an ancient Burmese city. Magnificent view.
  - TV Myanmar: United We Will Reach the Sky, NTSC VHS [TRT 01:30:00] (3 copies) (Box 297 and 303, Video-cassette BU246, BU246A and BU246B)
    The Rakhine (Yakhine) Regional Development projects
    Propaganda Film - cooperation between soldiers and people; The Rakhine traditional Kyin wrestling ceremony
  - TV Myanmar: Dream Sky, NTSC VHS [TRT 02:00:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU247)
    Propaganda for the Burma air force.
  - TV Myanmar: Growth - Nota Dream, NTSC VHS [TRT 01:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297and 303, Video-cassette BU248)
    SPDC's propaganda on general development under their authority. Social-economic development. Myanmar Oriental Bank. Myanmar's Business Convention Center. Shopping centers.
    Persuading foreign businessmen to invest in Burma. A traditional dance shown for business elite. Myanmar Airways. Burma's beautiful ancient treasures. Pagodas. Pagan an ancient Burmese city. Magnificent view.
  - TV Myanmar: Not Even Gold (1997), NTSC VHS [TRT 01:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 297, Video-cassette BU249)
    Sex trade prevention propaganda film
  - International Rescue Committee: Rescued Girls, NTSC VHS [TRT 01:23:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU250)
    Produced by: International Rescue Commtitee (IRC)
    HIV outbreak; rescued girls rehabilitation process.
  - International Rescue Committee: Women from the Camp, NTSC VHS [TRT 01:00:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU251)
    Women from Student Camps
    Situation is bad. It is an interview with a Burmese Girl: "My family is displaced and broken apart."
    The relentless oppression from junta.
  - International Rescue Committee: Refugee Information, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:40:00] (2 copies) (Box 303, Video-cassette BU252)
    Refugee Village in Thailand.
    Make shift dwellings and desperation.
    A refugee: "My father was killed when I was 6. We could not stay in Burma so I fled. Everyone wants to stay at home peacefully."
    "We need livelihood projects to prevent girls from being lured into flesh trade."
  - TV Myanmar: Mother was Once a Daughter, NTSC VHS [TRT 01:30:00] (4 copies) (Box 307, Video-cassette BU253, BU253A and BU253B)
    Film from SPDC-sponsored Mothers and Child Care Agency. TV Myanmar Production.
    Takes position of attacking opposition. Sexual harassment cases in Burma by foreigners. Abuse from foreign employers. Discouraging brain drain of Burma's best and brightest. Usually Myanmar elite. Staggering robust economy and people's responsibilities. Ever succeeding SPDC's economic plans and strict promotion of cultural value.
    Opposition is blamed for the economic demise and sanctions. This film seems intent on creating a rift between the people and opposition. Moral degradation and corruption among the people, especially the female population. An incredible friendship, unbelievable honesty,amazing leadership. Hardship among the people inflicted by sanctions. Family values, birth control campaign.
  - TV Myanmar: Our Pleasant Land, NTSC VHS [TRT 01:30:00](4 copies) (Box 307, Video-cassette BU254A and BU254B)
    Great Achievements of State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC)
  - TV Myanmar: Heaven and Earth Trembles, NTSC VHS [TRT 01:30:00] (3 copies) (Box 307, Video-cassette BU255, BU255A and BU 255B)
    TV Myanmar Film
  - Amateur Footage: Barefoot Soldiers, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 0:45:00] (2 copies) (Box 307, Video-cassette BU256)
    Produced by: Sophie and Linda Barry
    August 89 to September 1999.
    Burmese student army. A demonstration in Australia. Liberated zone. A Karen National Union (KNU) check point. A brief historyof death railroad. Up stream river Moi. (Thaung Yin Myit)
    Brief historical footage. U Aung San with Atlie.
    Footage from March 2, 1962, when New Win took power.
    All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF) camp. Scenes from 1988.
    Sein Lwin seen.
    Joy Titiken,a student: "We are rat poor. Soldiers shot and hundreds died, women were raped, Karen treated us like brothers and sisters unlike government propaganda."
    Hlaing Bwa :"Soldiers shot at us,young boy was hit but sergeant shot him point blank. We all have the same aim: we must fight for democracy."
    Rangoon hospital.
    Saw Maungand State Law and Order Restoration Council took over and Daw Aung San Suu Kyi came into picture.
    May Suu Tu Shey: "Children were shot at too; extreme bravery."
    Dr. Nge Lin: "Children were lost and drowned in Kan Daw Gyi."
    Ohn Gyaw, Foreign Minister for State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC): "Only twenty demonstrators and 525 looters were killed."
    Demonstration at Sydney, Australia. Cambara Burmese embassy
    Dr. Raymond Tint Way: "Past revolutions. Students are always the forefront of the causalities."
    Ways of torture under SLORC.
    U Thana Wara, a monk: "You can never understand how we suffered. I can never forgive them."
    Myo Thant: "We must fight to win. Only armed revolution will bring the desired result."
    Bo Mya: "We are fighting a dictatorship. We did not ask for a separate state but they brutalize us."
    Military training at Thi Baw Bo camp.
    May 1990 election "to improve the international image yet strictly controlled by army. Assembly of more than five people is banned."
    Ne Win's National Unity party lost election. National League for Democracy (NLD) won it.
    Saw Maung: "I'll do according to the law."
    Bo Hla Tint National League for Democracy: "Elected MP are being arrested, then we fled."
  - Amateur Footage: Street Demonstration August, 1988;Daw Aung San Suu Kyi Speech, NTSC VHS [TRT 01:00:00] (2 copies) (Box 290 and 307, Video-cassette BU257)
    In front of Tatmadaw Garden. People chanted: "To topple the dictator, our affair."
    U Wisara Monument."Democracy uprising will be successful."
    People gathered in west wing of Shwedagon Pagoda:
    "To gain democracy is our business."
    A makeshift stage, Bo Gyoke Aung San's portrait, thousands of people assembled.
    Seen are: Rangoon Bar Association,Nurses, Teacher's Training College.
    Very uneasy crowd. Announcement ofparticipating organizations.
    Daw Aung San Suu Kyi enters and takes stage.
    Speech: "Be disciplined. We want a multi party democracy system of governance. Students are the heroes. I stayed abroad, I am married to a foreigner, but it is wrong to think that due to such circumstances my love for Burma is less than anyone else. Our family knew the best how hard my father worked. I joined the uprising because this is the affair of the whole country. Being Bo Gyuke's daughter, I could not just sit back home. We can call this upraising the second struggle for independence based on the will of the people. Always united. Unity is the key for democracy. Discipline, peace is important. Students are fine and courageous and have shown physical strength. Hope to see their metal strength. No one is behind the students. Pure desire to gain democracy. I never support the political opportunists. We have already tried some. We need to try more.
  - APTV: Boy Soldiers from Burma, NTSC Betacam SP [TRT 00:03:00] (Box 290, Video-cassette BU258)
    Produced by: APTV
    Young soldiers in Karen National Union.
  - Burmese American Democratic Association (BADA) - San Francisco Meeting with U Soe Pyne (National Coalition Government of the Union of Burma [NCGUB]), NTSC VHS [TRT 01:00:00] (2 copies) (Box 290, Video-cassette BU259)
    Produced by: International Monitoring Institute (IMI) Analyst Pye Nyein
    July 26 2001, at Moon Star Restaurant in San Francisco.
    Burmese and American democracy advocates met. Heidi Quante present, U Nyunt Than, U Ko Ko Lay, U Sein Htun, UKyaw Tint and other Burmese meet. Happy faces. U Soe Pyne and Mrs. (National CoalitionGovernmentfor the Union of Very friendly Burma) NCGUB a special guest, Dr. Ye Myint.
    Heidi working toward Unocal withdrawal from Burma.
    U Soe Pyne (Interview):
    The dialogue: "We don't know the subjects. Daw Aung San Suu Kyiher self choose to keep secret. There are positive steps. Reopening of the offices."
    National League for Democracy (NLD) is officially invited to attend the Martyrs' Day ceremony.
    We cannot stop Japan from helping SPDC. Newspapers stopped attacking NLD.
    Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) has shown interest in changing Burma.
    We have connection with China. Sanctions have to be continued until we see full cooperation of SPDC.
    NCGUB will live as long as democracy is not installed in Burma. With many constraints and hindrances NCGUB is not functioning fully.
  - NHK: Burma on the Brink, NTSC VHS [TRT 00:30:00] (2 copies) (Box 290, Video-cassette BU260)
    Produced by: NHK
    Daw Aung San Suu Kyi over her fence:
    August 1995, where Burma heads. Seik Tine Gya Cafe(U Thaung Win 26): "Now good, child labor he is proud. Business sector does not care about human rights."
    New Thein Gyi Zay. Sprawling construction. Visit Myanmar in 1996.
    Ko Wanna, Political prisoner:
    A student: "Livelihood is more important. "
    A night club.
    A student in Japan: "Burma would be hopeless. We all want a better country."
    It's one month now, no change. It will never change. We don't want to go to jail."
    Under ground former prisoner very brave man: "People have spirit but fear being jailed. Prison life is hell; full of torture and abuse." Five days no food but interrogation for 24 hours. It's hard even to remember what is the truth ."
    Methods of torture: Strip the prisoner and have him sit on iceblock. Electric shocks, sat on his toes. Scars remained. Stuffed ear with match sticks and burn it. Ear drums blasted. Hit the face with sand bags. Eyes injured, teeth knocked out.
    There is no peace. Anger is suppressed with violence.
    Aung San Suu Kyi's press conference.
    U Chit Hliang, National Unity Party Chairman: "Suu Kyi's release is good for her but not sure if it is good for the country. She should understand the country is better. Dialogue is not important. State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC)decides."